CV of ABRAR HOSSAIN



5/U/1/B Borabo Mohonpur, Adabor, Mohammadpur, Dhaka 1207



+88-01686-072074



abrardipu@gmail.com & abrartuhin740@yahoo.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/abrar-tuhin-9094087a/



To be a dynamic Human Resource & Marketing professional, working in challenging environments that will enable me to enhance and utilize my skills and innate abilities efficiently, leading to self -development, and career progression, whilst employing my capabilities productively for my employer.

Career Summary

Develops policy and directs and coordinates Human Resources, Marketing activities, such as employment, compensation, Customer Service, Operation, labor relations, benefits, training, and employee services by performing the following duties.

Special Qualification

- Leadership
- » Fluency over English Speaking
- Team Work
- » Good ability over English Writing
- » Highly Numerate
- Strong interpersonal and communication skills
- Detail orientated

Working Experience (4 Years)

Officer, Institution & Tender (September, 2018 -Continuing)

(Contractual)

ACI Pure Flour Ltd. (ACI Ltd.)

Company Location: 245, Tejgaon I/A, Dhaka-1208

Department: Institution

Areas of Duties & Achievement:

- » Review of information about demands and derivation of supply and proposal preparations.
- » Clarification of bid conditions and management of the tender preparation



- » Monitoring of the bid management in order to ensure it is aligned with the organization's requirements
- » Contribution in cost and price calculations
- » Coordination of tender reviews and deadlines and adjust them to the frameworks given by the customers Coordination of tender reviews and deadlines and adjust them to the frameworks given by the customers
- » Provide senior management with input regarding current policies and practices of competition, when appropriate.
- » Attending Govt. Tender e-gp Tender (Army, Navy, RAB, Police ,SB,CID,SPBN Etc)
- » Attending International & National Tender NGO's Tender (WFP, Islamic Relief, Save the Children, ICRC, Red Cross, Etc.)
- » Customer Relationship International national chain shop Food Court Sales Forecasting, Target Etc.
- » New Product Invention, Idea generate Program Organized etc.

2. Executive, HR & Relationship & Inspection Management (August,

2017 - August 2018)

Cookups Technologies Ltd.

Company Location: 4D, 1st Floor, Road-74, Gulshan-2

Department: Business Development Areas of Duties & Achievement:

- » Conducted training needs analysis
- » Basic HR operation, ensure the overall growth and success of an assigned portfolio by deepening relationships with existing customers and new acquisitions.
- » Facilitated safe workplace practice and procedures in accordance with the requirements of Health and Safety legislation
- » Contributed in a creative approach to manage employee grievance
- » Learned to effectively communicate and coordinate with various departments
- » Checking and updating employee personal file and related all documents.
- » Updating employee personal information on ERP.
- » Checking employee dependent declaration information and update on ERP.
- » Taking employees exit interview and making report on that interview.
- » Making leave book and entry the leave on book.
- » Conducting daily inspection regarding hygiene and sanitation conditions of all production, storage areas etc.
- » Implementation of pest management program
- » Conducting in house audits
- » Documents inspection results by completing reports and logs; summarizing re-work and waste; inputting data into quality database

- » Coordinating with operation team to implement preventive and corrective maintenance
- » Approves incoming materials by confirming specifications; conducting visual and measurement tests; rejecting and returning unacceptable clients

3. HR Trainee [Contractual] (May, 2017 - August, 2017)

Genex infosys Ltd

Company Location: Uttara Mascot Plaza & Nitol Niloy Tower, Khilkhet.

Department: HR Operation

Areas of Duties & Achievement:

- » Created new hire folders and orientation paperwork
- » Created and organize existing and new employee files
- » Learned creating reports from HR databases
- » Created innovative job vacancy advertisement
- » Conducted training needs analysis
- » Assisted recruitment team in recruiting and selection process
- » Assisted performance review program
- » Facilitated safe workplace practice and procedures in accordance with the requirements of Health and Safety legislation
- » Contributed in a creative approach to manage employee grievance
- » Learned to effectively communicate and coordinate with various departments

4. Research Assistant [Contractual] (December, 2016 - February, 2017)

United International University

Company Location: Satarkul, Badda, Madani Avenue, Dhaka

Department: Institute of Business & Economic Research (UIU RESEARCH GRANT SCHEME-2016)

Areas of Duties & Achievement:

- » Working with academic members of the project team in order to deliver project outcomes
- » Responsible for writing up research papers and presenting research findings to supervisor
- » Converted quantitative data into qualitative demonstration with reasoning
- » Provided key stakeholders required information at every stage of process
- » Increased analytical skill through researching articles
- » Conducted critical questionnaire for survey
- » Learned data collecting techniques
- » Achieved reporting skills

5. HR Internee [Contractual] (August, 2016 - November, 2016)

Kazi Firms Group

Company Location: Road- 2. Dhanmondi

Department: HR

Areas of Duties & Achievement:

- » Checking and updating employee personal file and related all documents.
- » Updating employee personal information on ERP.
- » Checking employee dependent declaration information and update on ERP.
- » Taking employees exit interview and making report on that interview.
- » Making leave book and entry the leave on book.
- » Preparing confirmation latter, increment latter and send it to employee.
- » Making various kind vouchers.
- » Developing the organ gram of various department of Kazi Farms Group.
- » Preparing the performance appraisal and performance management form.
- » Calculated employee's behavioral and official performances.
- » Making Goal sheet for each employee.
- » Data entries of employees resume who are selected for the interview and those who are recruited.
- » Maintaining and updating database of the employees, file processing, updating personal files checking the documents of personal files.
- » Checking the references and sending mails. Maintaining the external resumes and preparing final settlement data.
- » Helping out the HR department when they are overloaded with work.

Contractual Work

- 1. bKash Ltd. (Customer Service Department) (April 2017 To June 2017)
- 2. AB IT Ltd. (Copy Writer, Data Entry Operator) (Jan 2016 To June 2016

Academic Qualification

(2017 -2019) Masters of Business Administration (MBA)

United International University
Human Resource Management & Marketing

CGPA: 2.86 out of 4.00

Achievement: 25% Scholarship

Post Graduate Diploma (PGDHRM) Professional Course (2016-2017)

United International University & BSHRM

Human Resource Management

CGPA: 3.72 out of 4.00

Achievement: 20% Scholarship

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

United International University
Human Resource Management & Marketing

(2012-2016) CGPA: 2.82 out of 4.00

(2009-2011) Higher Secondary School Certificate

Dhaka College
Business Studies

CGPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

(2007-2009) Secondary School Certificate

Mohammadpur Govt. High School

Business Studies

CGPA 5.00 on a scale of 5.00

Training Summary

1. Training Practical HR Title:

Training Institute: Alfah Training Academy

Topic: HR Planning and Recruiting, Employee Testing & Selection, Performance

management and appraisal, Ethics, justice and Fair Treatment Issues, Employee safety and Health Issues, Job Evaluation, Separation, Exit

Interview

Duration: 6 hours (20th October, 2017-27th October, 2017)

Location: Niketan, Gulshan

2. Training Sales & Marketing & Customer Service Title:

Training Institute: Jobs Training Academy

Topic:

• Negotiation Techniques
• Customer Service

Communication Skills

Social Media

• Email Marketing

Copywriting

Duration: 6 hours (20th October, 2017-27th October, 2017)

Location: Kawran Bazar, Dhaka

Professional & Technical Skills

» **HRIS** Moderate experience with HRIS, knowledge of the principles and practices of HR management.

» Labor Law Working knowledge of Bangladesh Labor Law along with the

requirements of Health and Safety legislation.

» IBM SPSS Have the ability to run Chi-square, One-way ANOVA, Two-way

ANOVA, Correlation, Regression and Reliability test.

Microsoft
 Word
 Can use Smart Art, textboxes, formatting, page setup, utilize the shapes and table creation

» Microsoft Excel Have the skill of financial data analysis, forecasting, ratio analysis,

beta, financial statement analysis.

» SPSS Moderate experience with SPSS, knowledge of the principles and

practices of Research management.

Language Proficiency

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bengali	High	High	High
English	High	High	Medium

Co-curricular Activities

- Senior Executive of HRM UIU Brand Forum in(2015-2016)
- » Marketing Executive of UIU Sports Club (2014 2015)
- Active member of HR Forum, UIU
- » Participated in Entrepreneurship & Innovation Expo -2013
- Volunteer, Path Finder (UIU Finance Forum)
- » Volunteer, CCC (United International University) Int. Career Summit.

Career & Application Information

: Mid-Level Job Looking For

Available For : Full Time

Present Salary : Tk. 25000 (Fixed + Variable)

Expected Salary : Tk. 30000

HR/Org. Development, Tender, Marketing, Office : Management Preferred Job Category

Preferred District : Anywhere in Bangladesh

Preferred Organization Types : Logistic/Courier/Air Express Companies, Public Relation

Companies, FMGO, Pharmaceuticals company, Consulting

Firms, RMG Sector, Food Commodity, FMGC

Personal Details

Father's Name : Afjal Hossain

Mother's Name : Halima Khatun

Date of Birth : October 1, 1993

Gender : Male

: Unmarried Marital Status

Nationality : Bangladeshi

National Id No. : 464 060 8487

Religion : Muslim (Sunni)

Permanent Address : Vill- Bagmara, PO- Shadordokhin, District- Comilla

Current Location : Dhaka

References

	Reference: 01	Reference: 02
Name	: Dr. Mohd Hasanur Raihan Joarder	Md. Mehdi Haque
Organization	: United International University	ACI Pure Flour Ltd.
Designation	: Professor, Director (IBER)	DM, Institution
Address	: Satarkul, Badda, Dhaka- 1209	245, ACI Center Tejgaon, I/A, Dhaka-1208
Mobile	: 01743331857	01708144585
E-Mail	: joarder@bus.uiu.ac.bd	mehdi@aci-bd.com
Relation	: Academic	Professional

.....

Abrar Hossain